Subham Dasgupta

subhamdq@outlook.com

Github, linkedin

Kolkata, West Bengal, India. | (+91)8240445647

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A city dweller who loves to travel, partake in outdoor activities. Currently a final year undergrad student of Computer Science and Engineering (B.Tech) from Amity University, Kolkata, major in Soft Computing and Al. Keen towards research and zestful about statistics, Machine Learning, IoT, Al, Big Data and Quantum Computing.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, C++, C, MATLAB, R
- Data Engineering and Data Visualization: numpy, scipy, pandas, matplotlib, plotly, ggplot2
- Machine Learning and Deep Learning: LSTM, GRU, Denoising AE, Hopfield Network, Deep Residual Network, Liquid State Machine, CNN, SVM, Neural Turing Machine, GANs, ENM
- **BigData:** Apache Spark, MongoDB, Hadoop, Amazon EMR (under training)
- Cloud: AWS EC2, Google Compute Engine, Vultr (under training)

EXPERIENCE

MyWBUT, Kolkata, West Bengal, India - Data Science Intern

April 2020 - June 2020

• Implementation of an End-to-End Autonomous Driving System using Behavioural cloning.

YapApp India, Ajitgarh, Punjab, India - Quantum Computing Intern

February 2020 - May 2020

- Implementation of quantum circuits in qiskit.
- Statistical analysis of various research methodologies.

Capital Methods, Ontario, Toronto, Canada - Undergraduate Research Intern

September 2019 - December 2019 (Remote)

- Implementation of various near-term quantum optimization algorithms for portfolio Optimization.
- Benchmarking quantum optimization algorithms with classical financial optimization algorithms.

EDUCATION

Amity University, Kolkata, West Bengal, India

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering with major in soft computing and Al

August 2017 - July 2021 (Expected)

IoT Captain of the IT club of Amity University, Kolkata (November 2017 - March 2018).

Vice-President (Student's Committee) of Entrepreneurship club of Amity University, Kolkata (June 2018 - April 2020).